Do you struggle to implement better data
storytelling techniques and want to make
effective communication a goal? Well, if
so, stick with me for the next few
minutes because I'll be demonstrating
via example the core lessons that we
will teach during our upcoming 8week
online course in which we'll teach you
how to plan, create, and deliver your
own data story through guided lessons
and practiced driven examples. and stick
with me until the end where I'll be
sharing a limited time special offer to
receive a discount on our upcoming
cohort which begins on the 15th of
September. Consider this slide which
came from a large organization that
recently conducted an advertising test
to drive incremental orders.
Unfortunately, despite the original
creators best efforts, it didn't drive
the intended action that they had hoped
for. In our scenario, let's imagine our
primary audience member is the marketing
manager. And while it was encouraging to
see that the ad campaigns helped drive
more orders, they were also at a
marketkedly higher customer acquisition
cost. As a result of this, we might
recommend just pausing to refine our
targeting strategy for more efficient
growth before resuming investment.
Now, we have our primary audience member
identified and the message that we're
looking to share. But before we go into
our tools and begin to create our
content, a little bit of low tech
planning can go a long way. And on the
team here, we advocate the use of
storyboarding or to put it another way,
the visual outline of your proposed
flow. Now, spending a bit of time here
at this stage can lead to faster, more
efficient creation of your slides
further down the road. Our initial
storyboard here as we build it up first
outlines the original goal of the
advertising campaign then explains the
test design and results and finally
offers a recommended next step. While
our initial storyboard was a pretty good
start, it was missing one vital and
critical component. Tension. Tension is
that magical element of story which
creates a sense of suspense for our
audience who are wondering what's going
to happen next and makes things truly
engaging and memorable. Reconsidering
our audience and the tension for them in
our ad spend story and focusing on the
elements of the data that truly matter.
The original storyboard is rearranged
into a narrative, an arc that shifts the
focus from the typical linear business
update to prioritize the needs and
interests of our audience. We turn our
attention to our graphs now and
transform our visuals using a series of
simple yet powerful design tactics.
thinking about the elements of our
visual that aren't helping our audience
understand the data and then applying
sparing color paired with explanatory
words. Doing this, we can help convey
our main message to our audience,
transforming those elements from that
busy data table into something more
straightforward while ensuring that we
make it clear where we want our audience
to look. It's only now that we move away
from our low tech planning tools and
begin to create our slides. This becomes
a simple transition from our storyboard
into our slide software. Following the
flow of the narrative arc, leveraging
corporate templates, we can build first
of all a digital skeleton of the content
before then beginning to flesh out the
rest of the detail of our presentation.
So after refining the content and
practicing our delivery, the final
presentation for our advertising
campaign scenario could look and sound
something a little bit like this. Hi
everyone, thanks for joining me here
today. In today's session, we've got a
couple of goals. First of all, to
discuss the findings from our recent
advertising campaign and then use those
results to better inform us on what our
marketing strategy might be going
forward. Now, to give ourselves a
reminder, we posed ourselves the
question at the outset of whether or not
higher ad spend would yield more orders
and acquire new customers. Now, the
short answer to this is yes, we can get
more orders, but it might not
necessarily be the best approach to
acquisition and growth. Let me explain.
Our test was pretty aggressive. We spent
four times the baseline amount to assess
the impact on orders compared to the
prior period. If we take a look at those
orders now, we have three distinct
buckets, three blocks of twoe periods.
Starting off with the baseline period
which was from the 22nd of March to the
4th of April. Before then we had that
spending increase of those two separate
two week blocks.
For the baseline looking back at the
past we had 439 orders. Now this is
pretty consistent with prior weeks and
the same period in prior years too. For
the test to be successful we should see
higher orders in these testing periods.
and we did, but it was just an 8%
increase, a modest increase, and lower
than we'd have hoped for, especially
given the increased investment. Despite
this though, there was an interesting
finding when we looked at the type of
customers. So, I'm going to break that
down now between new and existing. Just
shifting the visual type here to 100%
stack bars. And if we layer on our new
customers at the bottom, we do see that
the mix of those did increase during
that test around about double actually,
which is great news. However, it did
come at an added expense. We saw our
customer acquisition costs or CAC for
short marketkedly increase during that
testing period. For context, we went
from a CAC amount of $1.1,000
in that baseline period up to $2.2,000
$2,000 in those testing periods, two
times higher. So, while more customers
are great, I'm not sure they're that
great at double the cost. So, to answer
the original question, yes, spending
more does drive more orders and brings
in new customers, but it does drive up
the CAC substantially. Therefore, we
don't think it's an efficient use of our
marketing dollars. Instead, we recommend
just taking a step back, pausing for a
while, and developing better targeting
strategies to more efficiently attract
new customers. Thank you very much for
your time.
Check out the transformation from merely
showing data to presenting it in a
compelling way. And our 8week course is
structured with a specific focus for
each week's lesson. And so you'll go
from transforming raw data and a concept
in mind into a truly impactful project
by the end. And if you're keen to join
us, we'd love to see you in our upcoming
cohort. And here's that special offer
that I mentioned. For a very limited
time only, you can receive 25% discount
on the registration price. Details in
the video description and also on the
screen here as well. I hope you enjoyed
this transformation video. I look
forward to seeing you again soon. But in
the meantime, thanks for watching and
goodbye.